Cell: +1 (862) 684 – 5086 Jersey City, NJ Laura.kouadio@outlook.com

Laura KOUADIO

<u>LinkedIn Account</u> <u>Portfolio Website</u> GitHub Account

PROFILE & SKILLS

I focus my skills on data science and analytics to extract the best insights help you make meaningful decisions. I believe that working in a challenging environment is essential for personal fulfilment. With international communication skills and a good team spirit, I have a great ability to adapt to new cultures, and methods.

Tools and Languages: ARCHER, Excel, Google Sheets, JIRA, R, Power BI, PowerPoint, Python, SQL, Tableau, World **Softwares:** ARCHER, Google Cloud, JIRA, Jupyter, PyCharm, Anaconda, WebScraper, IBMWatsonStudio, GoogleCollab, Rstudio; Experience with economic research (statistics skills such as distributions, statistical testing, regression...)

Quantitative Research: Data Optimization (Scraping, Cleaning, Visualization, Analysis and Data Modeling)

Communication: English, French (Native Language), Spanish (Reading and Writing), Italian (Reading and Writing)

Certificates: IBM Data Science Professional (Coursera - 2021), Class QSO-645: Project Management for PMP Certification –

Certificate of Achievement

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MORGAN STANLEY- New York, United States of America

January 2023 - Today

RISK ANALYST – MODEL EUC METRICS (Firm Risk Management), ASSOCIATE FULL TIME

- Identification and Streamlining of FRM Models (224) and Tools (195) implemented in EUCs and Systems: managing lifecycle from identification to inventory decommission and monitoring controls on Models and Tools.
- Project Management for FRM Citizen Lead Development Applications: Implementing a Control Framework to mitigate Operational Risk on all Firm Risk Management Applications which fall under neither Systems, nor EUCs category.
- Analytics and Business decision reporting: Build and Maintain Business Intelligence Decks (Power Bi, Tableau, VBA Excel macros) to design metrics, create threshold and analyze data for business decision reporting.
- Regulatory Reporting for CCAR and QST: Report to the Bank Capital Steering Committee on controls for models implemented using EUCs.
- Key Control Validation: Independent Review of FRM Key Controls Design and Performance (56).
- IMS Enhancement and UAT Testing: Gather issues or improvement about IMS System Logic or IMS System Layout

RISK ANALYST – MODEL EUC METRICS (Firm Risk Management), ANALYST FULL TIME

August 2022 - January 2023

- Created dashboard through Business intelligence tools (Power BI, SQL, VBA) to create and showcase metrics
- Worked hands in Hand with Credit Risk, Market Risk and Risk Analytic Teams to improve EUC Control Metrics

SOCIETE GENERALE CIB - New York, United States of America

January 2020 - July 2021

RISK ANALYST PERMANENT CONTROL (Enterprise Risk Management), FULL TIME

- Maintained risk at the accepted level by assisting manager in the design of Level 1 controls and the change management around permanent control (project delivery, SG Group standard and norms update...)
- Identified areas of vulnerability from different angles through Business Intelligence Tools, consolidated and monitored anomalies and action plans for performance assessment
- Developed user requirements for project in issue management, interactions with developer's (JIRA tool)

SFR - Paris, France

September 2018 - August 2019

BUSINESS ANALYST (Commission/Finance), APPRENTICESHIP

- Elaborated reliable commission strategies: Created models and processes to analyse service providers performance and to study the effectiveness of the remuneration strategy of the company
- Collected and analysed data from different IS sources and reporting
- Produced cycles of commission for the internal control: Guarantee of reliability, conformity of calculations, control of deadlines and deliverables

EDUCATION

Master's Degree - Business Analytics and Quantitative Methods (GPA 4.0)

September 2021 - April 2022

SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY - New Hampshire, United States

Master's Degree - Audit, Management Accounting & Finance (GPA 3.6)

September 2017 - May 2019

SKEMA BUSINESS SCHOOL (AACSB Accredited) - Suzhou, China & Sophia Antipolis, France

Bachelor's Degree - Economics and Law PARIS NANTERRE UNIVERSITY - Nanterre, France September 2013 - June 2016

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & AWARDS

SNHU Cursus: Award of Academic Excellence - Graduated in two semesters (1 year) with a GPA of 4.0

Global Young Leader Program 2019: Hackathon at Ben Gourion University of the Neguev, Israel (3rd place Award)

SKEMA Gala Organizer: Setting up the Communication Style, Planning Operation and Entertainment, Hosting the Event

Sport: Weightlifting, Hit Workout, Biking